<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Vivi Hoang</title>
    <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Vivi Hoang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:02:32 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vivihoang.me/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Gender Impacts Requirements Engineering</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/papers/gender-requirements-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 14:50:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/papers/gender-requirements-engineering/</guid>
      <description>By Vivi Hoang
April 20, 2021
The tech industry continues to grapple with the lack of women and people of color in its ranks even as research has shown that diverse organizations perform better: The wider spectrum of backgrounds, experiences, identities and ideas may produce discomfort but they also produce innovation.1
This paper focuses specifically on how issues of gender impacts requirements engineering, the phase in software development that entails eliciting, documenting, validating and negotiating and managing stakeholder specifications for a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ethics of Software Engineering from the Lens of Library Science</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/papers/ethics-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 13:46:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/papers/ethics-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>By Vivi Hoang
Dec. 10, 2021
The fields of computer science and library and information science (LIS) have the capacity to learn a great deal from each other. Libraries grapple with budget issues while endeavoring to adequately serve their communities’ intellectual and practical needs. To better fulfill their mission and meet their patrons where they are, libraries have turned to digital products and services produced by software engineering professionals.
However, sometimes the aims of the two professions can conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Bias in Software Design and AI</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/papers/bias-in-software-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 10:09:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/papers/bias-in-software-design/</guid>
      <description>By Vivi Hoang
Dec. 10, 2021
Software, as a product of human design, by its very nature has our human worldviews encoded into it, whether intentionally or unintentionally. Artificial intelligence (AI) further plays out that facet of the system context, such as in the AI subfield of machine learning, in which algorithms evolve and adapt based on insights gleaned from large datasets.
By now, this spectrum of automation pervades our everyday lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySpace isn&#39;t private space</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/myspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:11:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/myspace/</guid>
      <description>By Vivi Hoang, staff writer
The Tennessean (Nashville, Tenn.)
Feb. 17, 2008
Franklin mom May-Ling Weitzman faked a Facebook page, creating an online alter ego with a different age, name and graduation date. Then she searched for her teen daughter&amp;rsquo;s page.
Her daughter wasn&amp;rsquo;t fooled by the subterfuge and spotted Weitzman, 48, from a mile off with great amusement. But mom made her point: Web privacy is, essentially, a myth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids get to the root of Tooth Fairy mystery</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/tooth-fairy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 18:54:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/tooth-fairy/</guid>
      <description>Youngsters share what they know about pixie who spreads love and cash    By Vivi Hoang, staff writer
The Tennessean (Nashville, Tenn.)
Sept. 18, 2006
Of all the childhood creatures lurking out there, one in particular has long baffled us.
Today we go in search of it, hoping to solve the mystery.
No, it&amp;rsquo;s not the bearded guy with a belly that shakes like a bowlful of jelly or the bunny with a penchant for unloading eggs at Easter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you want to know a secret? For Potter fans, answer is NO</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/harry-potter-spoilers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 18:47:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/harry-potter-spoilers/</guid>
      <description>By Vivi Hoang, staff writer
The Tennessean (Nashville, Tenn.)
July 22, 2007
Hear that? The crickets chirping?
It&amp;rsquo;s the vast abyss left behind by Harry Potter fans on voluntary lockdown. No TV, no radio, no Internet. They scored a copy of Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows soon after its release Saturday, and they&amp;rsquo;ve wisely hunkered down in an effort to outrace and outwit the spoiler mill.
&amp;ldquo;I plan on closing myself in a room and finishing it with hardly any sleep,&amp;rdquo; said Michelle Villeret, 15, of Sparta, Tenn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sisters preserve inspirational stories of Mama Rose</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/mama-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 18:44:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/mama-rose/</guid>
      <description>By Vivi Hoang, staff writer
The Tennessean (Nashville, Tenn.)
Nov. 25, 2007
The woman most people knew as Rosa Parrish was simply &amp;ldquo;Mama&amp;rdquo; in the eyes of her five children and &amp;ldquo;Mama Rose&amp;rdquo; to her brood of nine grandchildren.
Mama Rose is gone now, but her stories have been salvaged.
The longtime east Nashville resident died last year at age 67. To forever capture a few of their memories of Mama, three of her daughters ventured to the StoryCorps StoryBooth at the Nashville Public Library downtown earlier this fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maggie C’s magazine circle holds unbroken learning tradition</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/maggie-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:48:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/articles/maggie-c/</guid>
      <description>By Vivi Hoang, staff writer
The Tennessean (Nashville, Tenn.)
June 8, 2008
Maggie C is getting on in years but remains as healthy as the day she was born, 110 years ago, in Miss Lizzie Lee Bloomstein’s Nashville drawing room.
It was there that Miss Lizzie christened Magazine Circle, or Maggie C for short. What began as a unique study group of young Jewish ladies delving into magazines and issues of the times has become Miss Lizzie’s legacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;The Monstrumologist&#39; by Rick Yancey</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/monstrumologist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 14:59:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/monstrumologist/</guid>
      <description>Rick Yancey’s The Monstrumologist grabs you by the throat from Page 1 and doesn’t let go. The more you struggle, the more it gleefully squeezes you deeper into its gruesome clutches. And then it swallows you with a flourish and licks its chops.
That’s how over-the-top shivery and scary this riveting gothic tale is. Do you like monsters? Check. How about violence? Double-check!
You won’t be able to look away!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;I am a Genius of Unspeakable Evil and I want to be your Class President&#39; by Josh Lieb</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 14:38:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/genius/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember the Animaniacs, the Warner Brothers cartoon that ran from 1993 to 1998 (and that since returned in 2020)? It was an after-school favorite of mine. Funny, wacky, clever and subversive. It turns out those qualities still ring true with me. I found all of them in Josh Lieb’s I am a Genius of Unspeakable Evil and I Want to Be Your Class President. And while this book is geared toward kids, its story resonates with the evil genius in us all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;The Absolutely True Diary of a Part-Time Indian&#39; by Sherman Alexie</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/part-time-indian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 14:20:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/part-time-indian/</guid>
      <description>I finally got around to reading Sherman Alexie&amp;rsquo;s The Absolutely True Diary of a Part-Time Indian. It won the National Book Award for Young People&amp;rsquo;s Literature back in 2007 and I&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing fantastic things about it ever since.
The narrator of the tale, Junior, is now quite possibly one of my favorite characters. Ever. He will break your heart with his story even as he leaves you in stitches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;American Vampire&#39; by Scott Snyder</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/american-vampire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 14:11:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/american-vampire/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re of the school of thought that vampires should be neither sparkly nor mushy-hearted toward humans — that they should be depicted, instead, as stone-cold killers with moral compasses of dubious quality, then Scott Snyder&amp;rsquo;s American Vampire graphic novel series may be right up your blood-stained alley.
Volume 1 follows two separate storylines linked by one Skinner Sweet, a rabble rousing, blood drinking, candy chomping member of Vampire Version 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Londoners&#39; by Craig Taylor</title>
      <link>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/londoners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:30:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivihoang.me/writing/reviews/londoners/</guid>
      <description>In keeping with my U.K. kick started with Robert Galbraith&amp;rsquo;s The Cuckoo&amp;rsquo;s Calling, which features a careworn private eye in London, I mixed in the nonfiction book Londoners: The days and nights of London now—as told by those who love it, hate it, live it, left it, and long for it.
Over the course of five years, author Craig Taylor, a Canadian who moved to London, collected stories from 200 people in or from his adopted city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
